Farewell, Earth
The ship that is departing is
The Space Battleship
Yamato
It departs now to Iscandar,
at the end of the cosmos,
bearing its fate.
"We will come back, no matter what it takes"
Answer with a smile to the waving people
Going far from the Galaxy towards Iscandar
A faint gleam of hope
The Space Battleship Yamato
They, too, were fighting for what they believed in.
Our goals may have differed, but we pray the souls of both armies' soldiers
will return in peace to their home planets.
Salute!
Yurisha of Iscandar, huh?
When you were shot, I said to myself,
"I must return. I must get back to Hoshina."
And then Yurisha...
I'm glad you came back.
Yeah.
They survived, but they were all sucked outside the ship.
Ito may have died, but maybe he was right.
Don't be stupid.
But it doesn't make sense!
I thought that Iscandarian possessed Yuria, but then she shows up looking like Yuki.
Well, she's an alien. I guess they can do that.
I found it!
Idiot, not so loud!
S-Sorry...
What do we do now?
I'm thinking!
Enough...
See?
How are you feeling?
My Iscandarian isn't very good, so I put that on you.
I'm Banner Holder Norran Ortschett. I'll be looking after you for a while.
Something wrong?
Are you Garmillan?
We will soon arrive at the prison planet Leptapoda.
Everyone, prepare for landing.
Prison?
No, you'll be changing ships there.
Where are you taking me?
To Lord Desler.
Wait.
What happened to the Yamato?
The Terron ship sank.
Prison Planet Leptapoda
Someone of high birth will soon arrive here.
You will take care of her.
You barbarians just waste food.
<Hail to the Empire!>
They are Iscandarian royalty.
Someone from Iscandar?
Unfortunately, you're the only one who knows the proper etiquette.
<Hail to the motherland!>
What do you expect of one as old as I am?
UX01 is berthing... It's linked up. Lowering jetty.
Port crew, get ready.
Look at all those mechanical soldiers.
It's the same way everywhere.
We can't even maintain our territory anymore without those tin toys.
The downside to expansionist policy.
Where have you gone, invincible Garmillas?
Welcome to Leptapoda!
I am Bozen, Warden of Prison Planet 17.
Bring the Iscandarian to the car. This one will see to her.
That's General Domel's...
Yes.
This way.
Captain, I take my leave here, as well.
Where are you going?
I've been assigned the mission to return her to her home.
That's our task.
No room for second-class citizens.
We are also Garmillans.
Silence, you Zaltzi scum!
That bastard...
You are parasites on the Empire! You have no right to call yourselves Garmillans.
What? Don't look at me like that!
Stop.
Iscandar orders you... Fulfill your mission.
My father was a diplomatic officer,
so I was taught the proper etiquette as a child.
Please.
It looks good on you.
Thank you.
W-Wait.
I'm sorry.
What is that?
My sister gave this to me.
To bring salvation to sentient life on all planets.
That is the way of Iscandar.
And that is our clan's task.
Starsha...
This was the only planet in the surrounding system with the materials we need.
I've assembled an away team.
But first, this is within Garmillan territory.
It's possible that they recognize its value as well as we do.
Kodai,
I'm ordering you to carry out recon.
But I can't leave the Yamato right now...
Get some fresh air, okay?
Susumu Kodai will perform recon on the planet's surface.
I'll return to the brig.
Niimi...
The brig isn't where you should be going.
Yes, sir.
All guidance crew to their posts, and prepare for Seagull launch.
Repeat: All guidance crew to their posts, and prepare for Seagull launch.
You want to save her, Kodai?
What are you doing here?
Do you want to save Yuki?
Sorry, but I'm on a mission now.
I want to save her.
Would you get out? I don't have time to talk.
When will you have time?
I told you...
Seagull, are you ready to launch?
If I knew where she was, I'd save her... Anyway, would you get out?
She is on this planet.
Seagull, is there a problem?
No.
Roger. Opening hatch.
Is what you just said true?
Yes, here... She is here.
How can you tell?
I love her.
Don't you love her?
Well?
I-I...
Is this where we should be discussing love?
You're still alive?
Is that a problem?
No...
But it's good to see you taking it easy. Even after so many have perished.
Mori's cosplaying, huh? I'm jealous.
No, you probably don't know, but that isn't Mori...
I do know. She's an alien, isn't she?
Operations Officer Mori... Or perhaps Yurisha, of Iscandar.
It's not like that! Well, it is, but...
Don't move.
You...
You idiot!
I'm sorry!
Damn it!
Everyone, grab hold of something!
An imperial inspection ship?
Yes, it will arrive shortly.
Do you think they know what we've been selling on the black market?
Damn it! I finally had a chance to get back to the home planet!
No, I still have an ace up my sleeve.
I barely recognize you. You finally look like an Iscandarian princess.
Warden.
What?
A patrol has discovered what appear to be escaped prisoners.
I'm busy now...
We need to investigate! Get going!
That ship...
Out of the frying pan, into the fire, huh?
Your fault...
It's your fault.
It's your fault! If I hadn't listened to you, this never would've happened!
Yabu!
Message from the Warden!
Bring the Zaltzi woman to him at once.
<Unlocking>
What?
Wait!
Kodai!
Run!
<Are you a prisoner?>
<Fight with us!>
<Freedom will be ours!>
A riot?
Impossible...
But...
O-Oh hello, Inspector... I'm a bit busy now...
Huh?
This way.
You...
We've come for you, Admiral.
Security, report in!
We can't hold them! There are too many...
Let's get out of here.
Return to your rooms.
Freedom will be ours!
I'm sorry!
Are you okay?
Y-Yes...
This one...
He's a Zaltzi.
My comrade...
I won't let this stop me.
H-Hey, is anyone there? Open this door!
I'm right here!
<Glory to Gatlantis!>
Can you tell me where you're heading, Officer Mori?
To save Yuki.
I don't understand.
So aliens also mourn the dead?
Take care of mine.
Hey, Officer Mori, you...
Ito!
I guess acting out of character was a bad idea...
Mori...
If you really are an Iscandarian, would you make me a promise?
Take the Yamato to Iscandar. Please... Save Earth.
It appears subversive elements were aboard the Inspector's ship.
Confusion has occurred along the chain of command.
Yuki!
Prepare to launch!
Yuki... Yuki!
Yuki!
Attention all personnel.
I am Ditz, Supreme Commander of Astrofleets.
This prison planet is now under our control.
Cease all futile resistance, and surrender.
Yuki...
I know where she is going.
Yurisha!
Tell me... Where is she? Where?
Their planet... To Garmillas.
Two planets?
They are twin planets.
The one you are heading toward.
Our planet, Mother Iscandar.
No... That's impossible.
Episode 21
Prison Planet 17
Among the distant stars
Can you hear the wandering souls?
In this galaxy, they can forever rest in peace
Requiem of separation
With this requiem
Sing Along!
Voices sing to praise
An unforgettable memory
And we’ll never forget your name
Farewell friend,
my sorrow
Will not run out
Someday in this sea of stars
Surely
Pray for the Earth!
The oath
Pray for the dream!
The ideal
Last forever!
Iscandar offers Earth salvation.
Garmillas would destroy it.
The Yamato's destination, Iscandar, is a twin planet of Garmillas.
As they approach it, what
path should they take?
Is hope to be found there?
Next time: The Planet That We Head For.
There are 211 days left
before humanity is extinct.